<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Development on Hive Site</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/development/</link><description>Recent content in Development on Hive Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hive.apache.org/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Query File Test(qtest)</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/development/qtest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/development/qtest/</guid><description>Query File Test(qtest) Query File Test is a JUnit-based integration test suite for Apache Hive. Developers write any SQL; the testing framework runs it and verifies the result and output.
Query File Test(qtest) Tutorial: How to run a specific test case Preparation Run a test case Tutorial: How to add a new test case Add a QFile Generate a result file Verify the new result file Commandline options Test options Test Iceberg, Accumulo, or Kudu QTestOptionHandler: pre/post-processor Using test data Mask non-deterministic outputs Advanced Locations of log files Negative tests How to specify drivers How to use PostgreSQL/MySQL/Oracle as a backend database for Hive Metastore Remote debug Tips for Adding New Tests in Hive Tutorial: How to run a specific test case Preparation You have to compile Hive&amp;rsquo;s source codes ahead of time.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : GettingStarted</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/development/gettingstarted-latest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/development/gettingstarted-latest/</guid><description>Apache Hive : GettingStarted Apache Hive : GettingStarted Installation and Configuration Requirements Installing Hive from a Stable Release Building Hive from Source Running Hive Configuration Management Overview Runtime Configuration Hive, Map-Reduce and Local-Mode Hive Logging DDL Operations Creating Hive Tables Browsing through Tables Altering and Dropping Tables Metadata Store DML Operations SQL Operations Example Queries Simple Example Use Cases MovieLens User Ratings Apache Weblog Data Installation and Configuration You can install a stable release of Hive by downloading a tarball, or you can download the source code and build Hive from that.</description></item><item><title>QuickStarted</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/development/quickstart/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 17:51:06 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/development/quickstart/</guid><description>Introduction Run Apache Hive inside docker container in pseudo-distributed mode, inorder to provide the following Quick-start/Debugging/Prepare a test env for Hive
Quickstart STEP 1: Pull the image Pull the image from DockerHub: https://hub.docker.com/r/apache/hive/tags. Here are the latest images: 4.0.0 3.1.3 docker pull apache/hive:4.0.0
STEP 2: Export the Hive version export HIVE_VERSION=4.0.0
STEP 3: Launch the HiveServer2 with an embedded Metastore.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/development/gettingstarted/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 12:35:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/development/gettingstarted/</guid><description>The Apache Hive ™ data warehouse software facilitates reading, writing, and managing large datasets residing in distributed storage using SQL. Structure can be projected onto data already in storage. A command line tool and JDBC driver are provided to connect users to Hive.
Getting Started With Apache Hive Software Check out the Getting Started Guide. Learn more About Hive&amp;rsquo;s Functionality. Read the Getting Started Guide to learn how to install Hive The User and Hive SQL documentation shows how to program Hive Quick start with Docker Checkout the quickstart with Docker here: DOCKER_QUICKSTART</description></item><item><title>Version Control</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/development/versioncontrol/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:34:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/development/versioncontrol/</guid><description>Version Control The Hive source code resides in Apache&amp;rsquo;s Hive GitHub
Anonymous clone via http - https://github.com/apache/hive.git Authenticated clone via ssh - git@github.com:apache/hive.git Instructions: Apache committer git instructions</description></item></channel></rss>