<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apache Hive on Hive Site</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/</link><description>Recent content in Apache Hive on Hive Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 19:16:15 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hive.apache.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>QuickStarted</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/developement/quickstart/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 17:51:06 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/developement/quickstart/</guid><description>Introduction Run Apache Hive inside docker container in pseudo-distributed mode, inorder to provide the following Quick-start/Debugging/Prepare a test env for Hive
Quickstart STEP 1: Pull the image Pull the image from DockerHub: https://hub.docker.com/r/apache/hive/tags. Currently, there are 3 images released: 4.0.0-alpha-2 4.0.0-alpha-1 3.1.3 docker pull apache/hive:4.0.0-alpha-2
STEP 2: Export the Hive version export HIVE_VERSION=4.0.0-alpha-2
STEP 3: Launch the HiveServer2 with an embedded Metastore.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/developement/gettingstarted/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 12:35:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/developement/gettingstarted/</guid><description>The Apache Hive ™ data warehouse software facilitates reading, writing, and managing large datasets residing in distributed storage using SQL. Structure can be projected onto data already in storage. A command line tool and JDBC driver are provided to connect users to Hive.
Getting Started With Apache Hive Software Check out the Getting Started Guide. Learn more About Hive&amp;rsquo;s Functionality. Read the Getting Started Guide to learn how to install Hive The User and Hive SQL documentation shows how to program Hive Quick start with Docker Checkout the quickstart with Docker here: DOCKER_QUICKSTART</description></item><item><title>Hcatalog Downloads</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/general/hcatalogdownloads/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 20:28:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/general/hcatalogdownloads/</guid><description>HCatalog Merged With Hive Following HCatalog&amp;rsquo;s merge with Hive (in March of 2013) HCatalog is now released as part of Hive. Older versions of HCatalog can still be separately downloaded.
Old releases may be downloaded from Apache mirrors:
Download an old release now!
News 14 Feb, 2013: release 0.5.0 available This release introduces webhcat (a web services API to HCatalog), artifacts published in the maven central repository, and many improvements and bug fixes.</description></item><item><title>People</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/people/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 01:23:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/people/</guid><description>People Apache Hive is a community developed project. The list below is a partial list of contributors to the project, for a complete list you would have to look at all contributors to our issue tracker, mailing list and version control.
Hive PMC Apache username Name Organization Role aihuaxu Aihua Xu Cloudera athusoo Ashish Thusoo Qubole ayushsaxena Ayush Saxena Cloudera brock Brock Noland StreamSets ctang Chaoyu Tang Cloudera cws Carl Steinbach LinkedIn denys Denys Kuzmenko Cloudera daijy Daniel Dai Hortonworks ecapriolo Edward Capriolo gates Alan Gates Hortonworks gopalv Gopal Vijayaraghavan Hortonworks gunther Gunther Hagleitner Hortonworks hashutosh Ashutosh Chauhan Hortonworks VP heyongqiang Yongqiang He Dropbox jcamacho Jesus Camacho Rodriguez Hortonworks jdere Jason Dere Hortonworks jpullokk Laljo John Pullokkaran Hortonworks jssarma Joydeep Sensarma Qubole jxiang Jimmy Xiang Cloudera kevinwilfong Kevin Wilfong Facebook leftyl Lefty Leverenz IBM namit Namit Jain Nutanix navis Navis Ryu NexR nzhang Ning Zhang Facebook omalley Owen O&amp;rsquo;Malley LinkedIn prasadm Prasad Mujumdar Cloudera prasanth_j Prasanth Jayachandran Hortonworks pvary Peter Vary Cloudera pxiong Pengcheng Xiong Hortonworks rhbutani Harish Butani Hortonworks rmurthy Raghotham Murthy Facebook sershe Sergey Shelukhin Hortonworks spena Sergio Peña Cloudera sunchao Chao Sun Cloudera szehon Szehon Ho Cloudera thejas Thejas Nair Hortonworks vgumashta Vaibhav Gumashta Hortonworks vikram Vikram Dixit Hortonworks xuefu Xuefu Zhang Alibaba Inc ychena Yongzhi Chen Cloudera Hive Committers Apache username name organization amareshwari Amareshwari Sriramadasu InMobi apivovarov Alexander Pivovarov Foster City Hadoop Lab LLC asherman Andrew Sherman Cloudera ayushsaxena Ayush Saxena Cloudera bharos92 Bharath Krishna Cloudera chengxiang Chengxiang Li Intel chinnaraol Chinna Rao Lalam Intel cdrome Chris Drome Oath djaiswal Deepak Jaiswal Hortonworks dmtolpeko Dmitry Tolpeko EPAM dongc Dong Chen Intel ehans Eric Hanson Microsoft gangtimliu Gang Tim Liu Facebook harisankar Hari Sankar Sivarama Subramaniyan Hortonworks janaki Janaki Lahorani Cloudera jitendra Jitendra Pandey Hortonworks kgyrtkirk Zoltan Haindrich Hortonworks kuczoram Marta Kuczora Cloudera larsfrancke Lars Francke Freelancer mithun Mithun Radhakrishnan Oath mmccline Matt McCline Hortonworks mohits Mohit Sabharwal Cloudera ngangam Naveen Gangam Cloudera rbalamohan Rajesh Balamohan Hortonworks remusr Remus Rusanu Hortonworks sankarh Sankar Hariappan Hortonworks sbadhya Sourabh Badhya Cloudera sdong Siying Dong Facebook sseth Siddharth Seth Hortonworks szita Adam Szita Cloudera tchoi Teddy Choi Hortonworks vgarg Vineet Garg Hortonworks weiz Wei Zheng Hortonworks xuf Ferdinand Xu Intel yhuai Yin Huai Databricks PMC members are also Hive committers.</description></item><item><title>Issue Tracking</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/issuetracking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 01:05:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/issuetracking/</guid><description>Issue Tracking Hive tracks both bugs and enhancement requests using Apache JIRA. We welcome input, however, before filing a request, please make sure you do the following:
Search the JIRA database. Check the user mailing list, both by searching the archives and by asking questions.</description></item><item><title>Mailing Lists</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/mailinglists/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 01:01:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/mailinglists/</guid><description>Mailing Lists We welcome you to join our mailing lists and let us know about your thoughts or ideas about Hive.
User Mailing List The user list is for general discussion or questions on using Hive. Hive developers monitor this list and provide assistance when needed.
Subscribe: user-subscribe@hive.apache.org Post: user@hive.apache.org Unsubscribe: user-unsubscribe@hive.apache.org Archives: Apache Markmail Developer Mailing List The developer list is for Hive developers to discuss ongoing work, make decisions, and vote on technical issues.</description></item><item><title>Version Control</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/developement/versioncontrol/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:34:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/developement/versioncontrol/</guid><description>Version Control The Hive source code resides in Apache&amp;rsquo;s Hive GitHub
Anonymous clone via http - https://github.com/apache/hive.git Authenticated clone via ssh - git@github.com:apache/hive.git Instructions: Apache committer git instructions</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/general/privacypolicy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 19:35:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/general/privacypolicy/</guid><description>Privacy Policy Information about your use of this website is collected using server access logs and a tracking cookie. The collected information consists of the following:
The IP address from which you access the website; The type of browser and operating system you use to access our site; The date and time you access our site; The pages you visit; and The addresses of pages from where you followed a link to our site.</description></item><item><title>Downloads</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/general/downloads/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 19:16:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/general/downloads/</guid><description>Downloads Releases may be downloaded from Apache mirrors: Download a release now! On the mirror, all recent releases are available, but are not guaranteed to be stable. For stable releases, look in the stable directory.
News 14 August 2023: release 4.0.0-beta-1 available This release works with Hadoop 3.3.1 You can look at the complete JIRA change log for this release. 16 November 2022: release 4.</description></item><item><title>Javadocs</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/docs/javadocs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 04:01:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/docs/javadocs/</guid><description>Recent versions: javadoc and sources jars for use in an IDE are also available via Nexus Hive 4.0.0-beta-1 Javadocs Hive 4.0.0-alpha-2 Javadocs Hive 3.1.3 Javadocs Hive 4.0.0-alpha-1 Javadocs Hive 3.1.2 Javadocs Hive 3.0.0 Javadocs Hive 2.3.9 Javadocs Hive 2.2.0 Javadocs Hive 2.1.1 Javadocs Hive 1.2.2 Javadocs</description></item></channel></rss>