<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Generals on Hive Site</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/general/</link><description>Recent content in Generals on Hive Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 20:28:28 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hive.apache.org/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hcatalog Downloads</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/general/hcatalogdownloads/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 20:28:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/general/hcatalogdownloads/</guid><description>HCatalog Merged With Hive Following HCatalog&amp;rsquo;s merge with Hive (in March of 2013) HCatalog is now released as part of Hive. Older versions of HCatalog can still be separately downloaded.
Old releases may be downloaded from Apache mirrors:
Download an old release now!
News 14 Feb, 2013: release 0.5.0 available This release introduces webhcat (a web services API to HCatalog), artifacts published in the maven central repository, and many improvements and bug fixes.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/general/privacypolicy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 19:35:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/general/privacypolicy/</guid><description>Privacy Policy Information about your use of this website is collected using server access logs and a tracking cookie. The collected information consists of the following:
The IP address from which you access the website; The type of browser and operating system you use to access our site; The date and time you access our site; The pages you visit; and The addresses of pages from where you followed a link to our site.</description></item><item><title>Downloads</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/general/downloads/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 19:16:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/general/downloads/</guid><description>Downloads Releases may be downloaded from Apache mirrors: Download a release now! On the mirror, all recent releases are available, but are not guaranteed to be stable. For stable releases, look in the stable directory.
News 14 August 2023: release 4.0.0-beta-1 available This release works with Hadoop 3.3.1 You can look at the complete JIRA change log for this release. 16 November 2022: release 4.</description></item></channel></rss>