<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Generals on Hive Site</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/general/</link><description>Recent content in Generals on Hive Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hive.apache.org/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Hive : PoweredBy</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/general/poweredby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/general/poweredby/</guid><description>Apache Hive : PoweredBy Applications and organizations using Hive include (alphabetically):
Bizo We use Hive for reporting and ad hoc queries.
Chitika We use Hive for data mining and analysis on our 435M monthly global users.
CNET We use Hive for data mining, internal log analysis and ad hoc queries.
Digg We use Hive for data mining, internal log analysis, R&amp;amp;D, and reporting/analytics.
eHarmony We use Hadoop to store copies of internal log and dimension data sources and use it as a source for reporting/analytics and machine learning.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/general/privacypolicy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 19:35:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/general/privacypolicy/</guid><description>Privacy Policy Information about your use of this website is collected using server access logs and a tracking cookie. The collected information consists of the following:
The IP address from which you access the website; The type of browser and operating system you use to access our site; The date and time you access our site; The pages you visit; and The addresses of pages from where you followed a link to our site.</description></item><item><title>Downloads</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/general/downloads/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 19:16:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/general/downloads/</guid><description>Downloads All recent supported releases may be downloaded from Apache mirrors: Download a release now! Old releases can be found in the archives.
News 31 July 2025: release 4.1.0 available Apache Hive 4.1.x adds JDK 17 support and provides the Hive Metastore as a standalone component available in both binary and Docker image formats. Key improvements include enhanced Iceberg table support (storage-partitioned joins, partition-level column statistics, table compaction), IPv6 compatibility, a REST-based catalog server backed by the Hive Metastore, and upgraded Calcite to 1.</description></item></channel></rss>