<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Communities on Hive Site</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/</link><description>Recent content in Communities on Hive Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hive.apache.org/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Hive : BecomingACommitter</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/becomingcommitter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/becomingcommitter/</guid><description>Apache Hive : BecomingACommitter Becoming A Hive Committer The Apache Software Foundation defines generic guidelines for what it means to be a committer. However, it leaves the question of whether a particular contributor is ready to become a committer on a project up to the judgement of that project&amp;rsquo;s PMC. This wiki page attempts to explain what that means for the Hive project.
Committer Zen Contributors often ask Hive PMC members the question, &amp;ldquo;What do I need to do in order to become a committer?</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : Bylaws</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/bylaws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/bylaws/</guid><description>Apache Hive : Bylaws This document defines the bylaws under which the Apache Hive project operates. It defines the roles and responsibilities of the project, who may vote, how voting works, how conflicts are resolved, etc.
Hive is a project of the Apache Software Foundation. The foundation holds the copyright on Apache code including the code in the Hive codebase. The foundation FAQ explains the operation and background of the foundation.</description></item><item><title>People</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/people/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 01:23:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/people/</guid><description>People Apache Hive is a community developed project. The list below is a partial list of contributors to the project, for a complete list you would have to look at all contributors to our issue tracker, mailing list and version control.
Hive PMC Apache username Name Organization Role aihuaxu Aihua Xu Cloudera anishek Anishek Agarwal athusoo Ashish Thusoo Qubole ayushsaxena Ayush Saxena Cloudera brock Brock Noland StreamSets ctang Chaoyu Tang Cloudera cws Carl Steinbach LinkedIn denys Denys Kuzmenko Cloudera daijy Daniel Dai Hortonworks ecapriolo Edward Capriolo gopalv Gopal Vijayaraghavan Hortonworks gunther Gunther Hagleitner Hortonworks hashutosh Ashutosh Chauhan Hortonworks heyongqiang Yongqiang He Dropbox jcamacho Jesus Camacho Rodriguez Hortonworks jdere Jason Dere Hortonworks jpullokk Laljo John Pullokkaran Hortonworks jssarma Joydeep Sensarma Qubole jxiang Jimmy Xiang Cloudera kevinwilfong Kevin Wilfong Facebook leftyl Lefty Leverenz IBM namit Namit Jain Nutanix navis Navis Ryu NexR ngangam Naveen Gangam Cloudera VP nzhang Ning Zhang Facebook omalley Owen O&amp;rsquo;Malley LinkedIn prasadm Prasad Mujumdar Cloudera prasanth_j Prasanth Jayachandran Hortonworks pvary Peter Vary Cloudera pxiong Pengcheng Xiong Hortonworks rhbutani Harish Butani Hortonworks rmurthy Raghotham Murthy Facebook sershe Sergey Shelukhin Hortonworks spena Sergio Peña Cloudera sunchao Chao Sun Cloudera szehon Szehon Ho Cloudera thejas Thejas Nair Hortonworks vgumashta Vaibhav Gumashta Hortonworks vikram Vikram Dixit Hortonworks xuefu Xuefu Zhang Alibaba Inc ychena Yongzhi Chen Cloudera zabetak Stamatis Zampetakis Cloudera Hive Committers Apache username name organization amareshwari Amareshwari Sriramadasu InMobi apivovarov Alexander Pivovarov Foster City Hadoop Lab LLC asherman Andrew Sherman Cloudera ayushsaxena Ayush Saxena Cloudera bharos92 Bharath Krishna Cloudera chengxiang Chengxiang Li Intel chinnaraol Chinna Rao Lalam Intel cdrome Chris Drome Oath difin Dmitriy Fingerman Cloudera djaiswal Deepak Jaiswal Hortonworks dmtolpeko Dmitry Tolpeko EPAM dongc Dong Chen Intel ehans Eric Hanson Microsoft gangtimliu Gang Tim Liu Facebook harisankar Hari Sankar Sivarama Subramaniyan Hortonworks janaki Janaki Lahorani Cloudera jitendra Jitendra Pandey Hortonworks kgyrtkirk Zoltan Haindrich Hortonworks kuczoram Marta Kuczora Cloudera larsfrancke Lars Francke Freelancer mithun Mithun Radhakrishnan Oath mmccline Matt McCline Hortonworks mohits Mohit Sabharwal Cloudera okumin Shohei Okumiya Treasure Data rbalamohan Rajesh Balamohan Hortonworks remusr Remus Rusanu Hortonworks sankarh Sankar Hariappan Hortonworks sbadhya Sourabh Badhya Cloudera sdong Siying Dong Facebook simhadrig Simhadri Govindappa sseth Siddharth Seth Hortonworks szita Adam Szita Cloudera tchoi Teddy Choi Hortonworks vgarg Vineet Garg Hortonworks weiz Wei Zheng Hortonworks xuf Ferdinand Xu Intel yhuai Yin Huai Databricks PMC members are also Hive committers.</description></item><item><title>Issue Tracking</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/issuetracking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 01:05:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/issuetracking/</guid><description>Issue Tracking Hive tracks both bugs and enhancement requests using Apache JIRA. We welcome input, however, before filing a request, please make sure you do the following:
Search the JIRA database. Check the user mailing list, both by searching the archives and by asking questions.</description></item><item><title>Mailing Lists</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/mailinglists/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 01:01:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/mailinglists/</guid><description>Mailing Lists We welcome you to join our mailing lists and let us know about your thoughts or ideas about Hive.
User Mailing List The user list is for general discussion or questions on using Hive. Hive developers monitor this list and provide assistance when needed.
Subscribe: user-subscribe@hive.apache.org Post: user@hive.apache.org Unsubscribe: user-unsubscribe@hive.apache.org Archives: Apache Developer Mailing List The developer list is for Hive developers to discuss ongoing work, make decisions, and vote on technical issues.</description></item></channel></rss>