<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Resources on Hive Site</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/</link><description>Recent content in Resources on Hive Site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Hive : Books about Hive</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/books-about-hive/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/books-about-hive/</guid><description>Apache Hive : Books about Hive These books describe Apache Hive and explain how to use its features. If you know of others that should be listed here, or newer editions, please send a message to the Hive user mailing list or add the information yourself if you have wiki edit privileges. Most links go to the publishers although you can also buy most of these books from bookstores, either online or brick-and-mortar.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : Books, Blogs &amp; Talks</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/books-blogs-talks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/books-blogs-talks/</guid><description>Apache Hive : Books, Blogs &amp;amp; Talks Books: Programming Hive by Edward Capriolo, Dean Wampler, and Jason Rutherglen – O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media, 2012 Apache Hive Essentials by Dayong Du – Packt Publishing, 2015 and 2018 (second edition) Apache Hive Cookbook by Hanish Bansal, Saurabh Chauhan, and Shrey Mehrotra – Packt Publishing, 2016 Instant Apache Hive Essentials How-to by Darren Lee – Packt Publishing, 2013 Practical Hive by Scott Shaw, Andreas François Vermeulen, Ankur Gupta, and David Kjerrumgaard – Apress, 2016 The Ultimate Guide to Programming Apache Hive by Fru Nde – NextGen Publishing, 2015 Learn Hive in 1 Day by Krishna Rungta – independently published, 2017 Books primarily about Hadoop, with some coverage of Hive:</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : Building Hive from Source</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/building-hive-from-source/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/building-hive-from-source/</guid><description>Apache Hive : Building Hive from Source Fetching the source code Using the source tar: Download the source tar from [TODO: Put link post release] and untar From Git tag: Checkout the release tag using git clone &amp;ndash;branch rel/release-4.0.0 https://github.com/apache/hive.git Building Distribution Run: mvn clean install -DskipTests -Pdist -Piceberg -Pitests Find the built tar under packaging/target/apache-hive-* Running Unit Tests Run: mvn clean install -Piceberg Running Integration Tests GoTo itests directory Run: mvn clean test -pl itest -Piceberg</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : DeveloperGuide</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/developerguide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/developerguide/</guid><description>Apache Hive : DeveloperGuide Apache Hive : DeveloperGuide Code Organization and a Brief Architecture Introduction Hive SerDe MetaStore Query Processor Compiling and Running Hive Default Mode Advanced Mode Running Hive Without a Hadoop Cluster Unit tests and debugging Layout of the unit tests Debugging Hive Code Pluggable interfaces File Formats SerDe - how to add a new SerDe Map-Reduce Scripts UDFs and UDAFs - how to add new UDFs and UDAFs Code Organization and a Brief Architecture Introduction Hive has 3 main components:</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : DeveloperGuide UDTF</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/developerguide-udtf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/developerguide-udtf/</guid><description>Apache Hive : DeveloperGuide UDTF GenericUDTF Interface A custom UDTF can be created by extending the GenericUDTF abstract class and then implementing the initialize, process, and possibly close methods. The initialize method is called by Hive to notify the UDTF the argument types to expect. The UDTF must then return an object inspector corresponding to the row objects that the UDTF will generate. Once initialize() has been called, Hive will give rows to the UDTF using the process() method.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : Hive APIs Overview</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/hive-apis-overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/hive-apis-overview/</guid><description>Apache Hive : Hive APIs Overview This page aims to catalogue and describe the various public facing APIs exposed by Hive in order to inform developers wishing to integrate their applications and frameworks with the Hive ecosystem. To date the following APIs have been identified in the Hive project that are either considered public, or widely used in the public domain:
Apache Hive : Hive APIs Overview API categories Operation based APIs Query based APIs Available APIs HCatClient (Java) HCatalog Storage Handlers (Java) HCatalog CLI (Command Line) Metastore (Java) WebHCat (REST) Streaming Data Ingest (Java) Streaming Mutation (Java) hive-jdbc (JDBC) API categories The APIs can be segmented into two conceptual categories: operation based APIs and query based APIs.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : HiveDeveloperFAQ</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/hivedeveloperfaq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/hivedeveloperfaq/</guid><description>Apache Hive : HiveDeveloperFAQ Apache Hive : HiveDeveloperFAQ Developing How do I move some files? Building Maven settings How to build all source? How do I import into Eclipse? How to generate tarball? How to generate protobuf code? How to generate Thrift code? HIVE-26769 How to compile ODBC? How do I publish Hive artifacts to my local Maven repository? Testing How do I run precommit tests on a patch?</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : HowToCommit</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/howtocommit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/howtocommit/</guid><description>Apache Hive : Guide for Committers This page contains guidelines for committers of the Apache Hive project. (If you&amp;rsquo;re currently a contributor, and are interested in how we add new committers, read BecomingACommitter)
Apache Hive : Guide for Committers New committers Review Reject PreCommit runs, and committing patches Commit Backporting commits to previous branches Dialog New committers New committers are encouraged to first read Apache&amp;rsquo;s generic committer documentation:</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : HowToContribute</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/howtocontribute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/howtocontribute/</guid><description>Apache Hive : How to Contribute This page describes the mechanics of how to contribute software to Apache Hive. For ideas about what you might contribute, please see open tickets in Jira.
Apache Hive : How to Contribute Getting the Source Code Becoming a Contributor Making Changes Coding Conventions Understanding Maven Understanding Hive Branches Hadoop Dependencies Unit Tests Add a Unit Test Submitting a PR Fetching a PR from Github Contributing Your Work JIRA Guidelines Generating Thrift Code See Also Getting the Source Code First of all, you need the Hive source code.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : HowToRelease</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/howtorelease/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/howtorelease/</guid><description>Apache Hive : HowToRelease Apache Hive : HowToRelease Introduction Storage API Release Storage API Prepare Master Branch Storage API Branching Making Storage API Release Artifacts Publishing the Storage API Artifacts Preparing Branch for further development Cleaning Up Storage API Artifacts Hive Release Preparation Branching Updating Release Branch Building Voting Verifying the Release Candidate Publishing Archive old releases Preparing Branch for Future Maintenance Release See Also Introduction This page is prepared for Hive committers.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : MetaStore API Tests</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/metastore-api-tests/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/metastore-api-tests/</guid><description>Apache Hive : MetaStore API Tests IMetaStoreClient Tests IMetaStoreClient Tests One option for Java clients to access the MetaStore is to connect through the IMetaStoreClient interface implementations.
To ensure that the IMetaStoreClient implementations provide the same API we created a set of tests to validate their workings.
Currently the following implementations are tested:
EmbeddedMetaStore – when the MetaStore is running in the same thread, and in process communication is used.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : Performance</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/performance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/performance/</guid><description>Apache Hive : Performance YourKit Java Profiler Collaboration To measure Hive&amp;rsquo;s internal performance, we use the YourKit Java Profiler. YourKit LLC is kindly supporting open source projects with its full-featured Java Profiler. The Hive project has been granted YourKit open source licenses to be used by its developers. For more information on this collaboration, ask on the developers mailing list.
 Benchmarks Here are some JIRA issues about benchmarks for Hive:</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : PluginDeveloperKit</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/plugindeveloperkit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/plugindeveloperkit/</guid><description>Apache Hive : PluginDeveloperKit Hive Plugin Developer Kit This page explains Apache Hive&amp;rsquo;s Plugin Developer Kit, or PDK. This allows developers to build and test Hive plugins without having to set up a Hive source build; only a Hive binary release is needed.
The PDK is planned for inclusion in the Hive 0.8.0 release; until that is available, please download a recent snapshot build from Jenkins; make sure it includes HIVE-2244.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : Presentations</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/presentations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/presentations/</guid><description>Apache Hive : Presentations Apache Hive : Presentations Hive Meetups January 2016 Hive User Group Meetup November 2015 Hive Contributor Meetup April 2015 Hive Contributor Meetup Presentations February 2015 Hive User Meetup Presentation November 2013 Hive Contributors Meetup Presentations June 2013 Hadoop Summit Hive Meetup Presentations February 2013 Hive User Group Meetup June 2012 Hadoop Summit Hive Meetup Presentations November 2011 NYC Hive Meetup Presentations Older Hive Presentations Related Work Attachments: Hive Meetups January 2016 Hive User Group Meetup attachments/27362054/61337098-pptx attachments/27362054/61337312-ppsx attachments/27362054/61337398-ppsx Hive on Spark: now and future - Xuefu Zhang November 2015 Hive Contributor Meetup attachments/27362054/61329032-pptx attachments/27362054/61329033-pptx attachments/27362054/61329034-pptx attachments/27362054/61329036-pptx attachments/27362054/61329038-pptx attachments/27362054/61329039.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : RelatedProjects</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/relatedprojects/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/relatedprojects/</guid><description>Apache Hive : RelatedProjects Shark Shark is a fork of Apache Hive that uses Spark in place of MapReduce.
Apache Hivemall (incubating) Apache Hivemall is a scalable machine learning library for Apache Hive, Apache Spark, and Apache Pig.
Apache Sentry (incubating) Sentry is a role-based authorization system for Apache Hive.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : Running Yetus</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/running-yetus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/running-yetus/</guid><description>Apache Hive : Running Yetus Overview Yetus is added to Hive in release 3.0.0 to run checks on the new patches. See HIVE-15051.
There are several rules already defined by the community, but most of them are not enforced.
Yetus helps us by checking these rules for newly introduced errors. Note that Yetus checks only the changed part of the code. If any unchanged code contains errors, then Yetus will not report them, but all of the new code should conform to the rules.</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : TestingDocs</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/testingdocs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/testingdocs/</guid><description>Apache Hive : TestingDocs Hive Testing Documents The following documents describe aspects of testing for Hive:
Hive Developer FAQ: Testing Developer Guide: Unit Tests Unit Testing Hive SQL Running Yetus MetaStore API Tests Query File Test(qtest)</description></item><item><title>Apache Hive : Unit Testing Hive SQL</title><link>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/unit-testing-hive-sql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hive.apache.org/community/resources/unit-testing-hive-sql/</guid><description>Apache Hive : Unit Testing Hive SQL Apache Hive : Unit Testing Hive SQL Motivations Challenges Modularisation Encapsulation of column level logic Encapsulation of set level logic Tools and frameworks Useful practices Relevant issues Other Hive unit testing concerns Motivations Hive is widely applied as a solution to numerous distinct problem types in the domain of big data. Quite clearly it is often used for the ad hoc querying of large datasets.</description></item></channel></rss>